Preliminary Inventory to the David Edward Charles Eversley Papers, 1935-1994
Hoover Institution Archives
David Edward Charles Eversley Papers,
1935-1994
89008
Eversley, David Edward Charles
178 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes, 3 linear feet (82.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Speeches and writings, correspondence, studies, reports, memoranda, notes, agenda, minutes, statistical data, printed matter, and maps, relating to population studies, including urbanization, immigration, and family planning; and urban and regional planning, including housing and other social and economic planning aspects, especially in London, elsewhere in England, Northern Ireland, and West Germany.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1989.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Greater London Council.; City planning--England--London.; London (England); Great Britain--Social policy.; Great Britain--Economic policy--1945-; Housing--England--London.; Regional planning--Great Britain.; Great Britain.; Population.; Urbanization.; Rural-urban migration.; Emigration and immigration.; Fertility, Human.; Northern Ireland.; Ireland.; Germany (West); Germany.
Container List
- Speeches and writings. Proofs, typescripts, outlines, correspondence, charts, and bulletins; includes manuscripts entitled "Rising Costs and Static Incomes: Some Consequences of Regional Planning in London" and "The Planner in Society: An Essay on the Future of British Planning," 1943-1975 (Box 1-3)
- Center for Environmental Studies, Social Science Research Council. Reports, correspondence, clippings, memoranda, charts, printed articles, lists, notes, press releases, and administrative material, 1967-1988 (Box 4-11)
- Greater London Council. Correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed articles, clippings, charts, and miscellany, 1963-1983
  - General (Box 12-18)
    - General. Includes material relating to transportation, housing, health and safety, town planning, employment, architecture, and the Strategic Programme Planning Board
    - Commercial and industrial development (Box 19-23)
    - Docklands (Box 24-25)
    - Housing. Includes material relating to immigrants, home ownership, and land availability (Box 26-29)
  - Greater London Development Project. Reports, memoranda, notes, correspondence, printed articles, hearing transcripts, press releases, charts, and miscellany, 1970-1978
    - General
      - General (Box 30-38)
      - Reports (Box 39-50)
      - Transcripts (Box 51-63)
  - "Tomorrow's London". Reports, memoranda, correspondence, notes, typescripts, clippings, and photographs, 1968-1970 (Box 64-66)
- London Tourism Board. Clippings, reports, correspondence, pamphlets, and memoranda; includes some material relating to census data, housing, and the Greater London Council, 1968-1972 (Box 67-68)
- Overseas population and fertility. Reports, program statements, pamphlets, manuals, printed articles, and miscellany; includes material relating to urbanization, migration and immigration, family planning, and public health, 1963-1981 (Box 69-72)
- Population and planning conferences. Pamphlets, correspondence, printed material, notes, memoranda, reports, agenda, and miscellany, 1967-1979 (Box 73-85)
- Regional Studies Association. Printed articles, notes, charts, questionnaires, correspondence, reports, agenda, minutes, clippings, and lists, 1982-1983 (Box 86)
- Standing Conference on London and South East Regional Planning. Memoranda, reports, notes, and correspondence, 1966-1979 (Box 87-88)
- Incremental materials (Box 89-182)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.